<!DOCTYPE book [
<!ENTITY Scaron "&#x160;">
<!ENTITY ccaron "&#x10D;">
<!ENTITY aacute "&#x0E1;">
<!ENTITY mdash "&#8212;">
<!ENTITY ouml "&#xf6;">]>
<!--
 - Copyright (C) Internet Systems Consortium, Inc. ("ISC")
 -
 - This Source Code Form is subject to the terms of the Mozilla Public
 - License, v. 2.0. If a copy of the MPL was not distributed with this
 - file, You can obtain one at http://mozilla.org/MPL/2.0/.
 -
 - See the COPYRIGHT file distributed with this work for additional
 - information regarding copyright ownership.
-->

<section xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0"><info/>
  <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="noteversion.xml"/>
  <section xml:id="relnotes_intro"><info><title>Introduction</title></info>
    <para>
      This is a release of the BIND 9.11 Supported Preview Edition, a
      special feature preview branch of BIND which is available to ISC
      customers.
    </para>
    <para>
      This document summarizes significant changes since the last
      production release on the BIND 9.11 (Extended Support Version) branch.
      Please see the file CHANGES for a complete list of bug fixes and
      other changes, or CHANGES.SE for a list of changes that have been
      applied specifically to the Supported Preview edition.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="relnotes_download"><info><title>Download</title></info>
    <para>
      The latest versions of BIND 9 software can always be found at
      <link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.isc.org/downloads/">http://www.isc.org/downloads/</link>.
      There you will find additional information about each release,
      source code, and pre-compiled versions for Microsoft Windows
      operating systems.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="win_support"><info><title>Legacy Windows No Longer Supported</title></info>
    <para>
      As of BIND 9.11.2, Windows XP and Windows 2003 are no longer supported
      platforms for BIND; "XP" binaries are no longer available for download
      from ISC.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="relnotes_security"><info><title>Security Fixes</title></info>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  There was a long-existing flaw in the documentation for
	  <command>ms-self</command>, <command>krb5-self</command>,
	  <command>ms-subdomain</command>, and
	  <command>krb5-subdomain</command> rules in
	  <command>update-policy</command> statements.  Though the
	  policies worked as intended, operators who configured their servers
	  according to the misleading documentation may have thought zone
	  updates were more restricted than they were; users of these rule
	  types are advised to review the documentation and correct their
	  configurations if necessary.  New rule types matching the
	  previously documented behavior will be introduced in a future
	  maintenance release. [GL !708]
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  <command>named</command> could crash during recursive processing
	  of DNAME records when <command>deny-answer-aliases</command> was
	  in use. This flaw is disclosed in CVE-2018-5740. [GL #387]
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  A merge error when backporting the <command>serve-stale</command>
	  feature could cause the resolver to send too many queries; this
	  could potentially have been exploited in an amplification attack.
	  [GL #611]
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="relnotes_features"><info><title>New Features</title></info>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  When acting as a recursive resolver, <command>named</command> can
	  now continue returning answers whose TTLs have expired when the
	  authoritative server is under attack and unable to respond. This
	  is controlled by the <command>stale-answer-enable</command>,
	  <command>stale-answer-ttl</command> and
	  <command>max-stale-ttl</command> options. [RT #44790]
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Added support for forwarding queries to Cisco
	  Umbrella servers, when built with
	  <command>configure --enable-umbrella</command>. [GL #229]
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  The <command>dnskey-sig-validity</command> option allows the
	  <command>sig-validity-interval</command> to be overriden for
	  signatures covering DNSKEY RRsets. [GL #145]
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  The <command>validate-except</command> option specifies a list of
	  domains beneath which DNSSEC validation should not be performed,
	  regardless of whether a trust anchor has been configured above
	  them. [GL #237]
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Two new update policy rule types have been added,
	  <command>krb5-selfsub</command> and <command>ms-selfsub</command>,
	  which allow machines with Kerberos principals to update
	  the name space at or below the machine names identified
	  in the respective principals.
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="relnotes_bugs"><info><title>Bug Fixes</title></info>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Running <command>rndc reconfig</command> could cause
	  <command>inline-signing</command> zones to stop signing. [GL #439]
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Reloading all zones caused zone maintenance to stop for
	  <command>inline-signing</command> zones. [GL #435]
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Signatures loaded from the journal for the signed version of an
	  <command>inline-signing</command> zone were not scheduled for
	  refresh. [GL #482]
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  The <command>rndc nta</command> command could not differentiate
	  between views of the same name but different class; this
	  has been corrected with the addition of a <command>-class</command>
	  option. [GL #105]
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  When compiled with IDN support, the <command>dig</command> and the
	  <command>nslookup</command> commands now disable IDN processing when
	  the standard output is not a tty (e.g. not used by human).  The command
	  line options +idnin and +idnout need to be used to enable IDN
	  processing when <command>dig</command> or <command>nslookup</command>
	  is used from the shell scripts.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  When a negative trust anchor was added to multiple views
	  using <command>rndc nta</command>, the text returned via
	  <command>rndc</command> was incorrectly truncated after the
	  first line, making it appear that only one NTA had been
	  added. This has been fixed. [GL #105]
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="end_of_life"><info><title>End of Life</title></info>
    <para>
      BIND 9.11 (Extended Support Version) will be supported until at
      least December, 2021.
      BIND 9.11-S (Supported Preview Edition) releases will continue to
      be published in tandem with BIND 9.11 releases until the Supported
      Preview Edition moves to a new branch. This may happen before BIND 9.11
      reaches end of life, but not later. See
      <link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.isc.org/downloads/software-support-policy/">https://www.isc.org/downloads/software-support-policy/</link> for details of ISC's software support policy.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="relnotes_thanks"><info><title>Thank You</title></info>

    <para>
      Thank you to everyone who assisted us in making this release possible.
      If you would like to contribute to ISC to assist us in continuing to
      make quality open source software, please visit our donations page at
      <link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://www.isc.org/donate/">http://www.isc.org/donate/</link>.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>
